Guide to the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization home economics publications, 1960-1988.
United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization home economics publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization home economics publications, 1960-1988.
4910
Jenkins, Ludmilla A.,
2 cubic ft.
Publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Publications relating to the work of FAO and other organizations. Subjects include home economics, planning, child care, food and nutrition, textiles and clothing, consumer education, the role of women, and family issues, particularly in Africa.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Ludmilla A. Marin (Jenkins) was the head of Home Economics for FAO.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications relating to the work of FAO and other organizations. Subjects include home economics, planning, child care, food and nutrition, textiles and clothing, consumer education, the role of women, and family issues, particularly in Africa.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Jenkins, Ludmilla A.,; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; United Nations. Food and Agriculture Organization.
Subjects:
Home economics -- Study and teaching.; Child care.; Textile fabrics.; Consumer education.; Child care; Consumer education; Home economics -- Study and teaching; Textile fabrics
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Informe del Taller de Capacitacion Sobre Evaluacion de Proectos de Generacion de Ingresos Con Mujeres Campesinas, 1988-04-12-1988-04-15; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 36 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Santiago, Chile; April 12th to 15th, 1988
- Information on Some Aspects of Family and Home Economics Research in Europe, 1971-08; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 40 pp (Box 1)
- Planning for Better Family Living Report Series no. 9: Workshop for Village Polytechnics Domestic Science Teachers, 1973-07-30 -1973-08-11; The Government of Kenya; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 81 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Karen College, Nairobi, Kenya; July 30th to August 11th, 1973
- Mejoramiento del Hogar: Trabajos del Taller Seminario, 1977-07-18-1977-07-20; Centro Internacional de Investigaciones para el Desarollo, CIID, de Canadá; 96 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Guatemala; July 18th to 20th, 1977
- Strengthening Programs in Home Economics in the Western Hemisphere, 1978-08-08 -1978-08-11; International Federation for Home Economics (Region of the Americas); Associacion Latinoamericana de Educadoras del Hogar; 39 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Guatemala City, Guatemala; August 8th to 11th, 1979
- Manual de Corte y Costura, 1958; Pérez, María Luisa de; Servicio de Informacion y de Extension Consejo de Bienestar Rural; 105 pp (Box 1)
- Report of the European Seminar on Evaluation of Home Economics Extension Programs, 1960-05-09-1960-05-21; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 50 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Vienna, Austria; May 9th to 21st, 1960
- Hanover Street: An Experiment to Train Women in Welding and Carpentry, 1980; Antrobus, Peggy; Rogers, Barbara; SEEDS; 16 pp (Box 1)
- Manual Para Evaluacion de Proyectos, 1991; Oficina Regional Para America Latina y El Caribe; 91 pp (Box 1)
  Three booklets in a paper case
- Population, Family Life and Resources: A Population Education Curriculum Guide, 1974; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 103 pp | 40 inserts (Box 1)
- Report of the SPC/FFHC Project for the Extension of the Educational Facilities in the South Pacific Region, 1967; Crowley, Margaret; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 32 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Malaysia on Development of Home Economics Programmes, West Malaysia, 1969-1972, 1972; Purvis, Barbara M.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 46 pp (Box 1)
- Report on the FAO/Danish Reminar on Long-Term Planning of Home Economics for Selected English-Speaking Countries in Africa, 1968-06-23-1968-07-13; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 40 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Aarhus, Denmark; June 23rd to July 13th, 1968
- Older Farmers in Europe: The Social Situation of the Older Farm Popuulation in a Changing Rural Environment, 1975; Baldwin, K.D.S.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 27 pp (Box 1)
- Report on the FAO/UNFPA Inter-Country Workshop on Population Education for Small Farmer Development, 1977-11-29-1977-12-08; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 56 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Quezon City, Philippines; November 29th to December 8th, 1977
- Long-Term Planning in Home Economics for Europe: A Summary Report of Information Collected from an FAO Enquiry Sheet to European Member Governments, 1969; Pranttila, Anneli; European Commission on Agriculture Working Party on Home Economics; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 62 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Tanzania: Home Economics Training Centre for Women and Girls, Musoma, Tanzania, 1969; Bergstrom, Greta; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 39 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Tanzania on Training in Textiles and Clothing of Rural Development Instructors, 1969; Winka, Gunnel; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 9 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Tanzania: Training in Food and Nutrition of Rural Development Instructors, 1969; Berg, Greta; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 20 pp (Box 1)
- Planning for Better Family Living: Questions and Answers, 1972; Graves, Patsy; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 10 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Nigeria: A Preliminary Study on Home Economics Planning for Rural Development, 1970; Janelid, Ingrid; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 25 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Swaziland on the Development of a Home Economics Diploma Course at the Swaziland Agriculture College and University Centre, 1971; Montgomery, Wanda; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 23 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Ethiopia on the Preliminary Study of the Planning of Home Economics Programmes for National Development, 1971; Janelid, Ingrid; Ethiopian Inter-Agency Ad Hoo Committee on Home Economics; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 43 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Lesotho on Revision of a Rural Domestic Economy Certificate Course, 1971; Montgomery, Wanda; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 23 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Botswana on the Development of a Home Economics Programme, 1971; Montgomery, Wanda; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 25 pp (Box 1)
- Learning from Rural Women: Village-Level Success Cases of Rural Women's Group Income-Raising Activities, 1979; ESCAP/FAO Inter-country Project for the Promotion and Training of Rural Women in Income-raising Group Activities; 142 pp (Box 1)
- Report on the FAO/UNFPA Workshop on Population Education in the In-Service Staff Training Programmes of Rural Development Agencies in Asia and the Far East, 1976; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 54 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Peradenia, Sri Lanka; November 19th to 28th, 1975
- Population, Food Supply and Agricultural Development, 1975; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 68 pp (Box 1)
- Technical Report Strengthening the Home Economics Section of the Relief and Rehabilitation Commission, 1983; Hamada, D. M.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 26 pp (Box 1)
- Report of the FAO/SIDA Workshop on the Integration of Women in Agriculture and Rural Development, 1981; The National Institute of Rural Development; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 43 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Hyderabad, India; November, 17th to 22nd, 1980
- Report on the FAO/SIDA Project "Promoting the Participation of Women in Rural Development", 1981; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 29 pp (Box 1)
- The Role of Women in Nigerian Agriculture, 1975; Janelid, Ingrid; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 16 pp (Box 1)
  Based on a paper presented at a "National Seminar on Home Economics Development Planning", Ibadan, Nigeria, December 1st to 6th, 1974
- Integrated Functional Education in Machakos District: The Introduction of Population Education into Rural Extension Services, 1974; Barghouti, Shawki M.; Programmes for Better Family Living; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 29 pp (Box 1)
- Curriculum Development for Bukura Institute of Agriculture, 1975; Programmes for Better Family Living; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 116 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Institute of Adult Studies, University of Nairobi; May 8th to 11th, 1974
- Report to the Government of Nigeria on Home Economics Planning for Rural Development, 1977; Morenas, Y.; Weidemann, C. J.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 73 pp (Box 1)
- Report of the ECA Training Workshop on Communication, Planning Techniques, and Adult Education, 1977; Government of Zambia; United Nations Economic Commission for Africa; 100 pp (Box 1)
- Report of a Workshop for Trainers of Rural Women Leaders, 1977; Government of Sudan; United Nations Economics Commission for Africa; 139 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Khartoum, Sudan; September 1976
- Report of the Consultancy on the Role of Home Economics in Promoting Agricultural Development and Food Security in Africa, 1985-10; Home Economics Association of Africa (HEAA); 33 pp (Box 1)
  Two copies
- Report on the Seminar on the Role of Women in Integrated Rural Development with Emphasis on Population Problems, 1975; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 85 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Cairo, Egypt; October 26th to November 3rd, 1974
- Summary Report of the FAO Regional Population Workshop for Latin America, 1975; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 46 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Santiago, Chile; October 10th to November 1st, 1974
- The Integration of Women in Rural Development in Peru: Notes on Selected Information Available at FAO Headquarters, 1978; 30 pp (Box 1)
- The Changing Role of Arab Women, 1978; Zurayk, Huda; United Nations Economic and Social Council; 23 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Amman, Jordan; November 18th to 20th, 1978
- Integration of Women in Rural Development: Review and Analysis of FAO Policies, Programmes (1975-79) and Future Programme Trends (1980-85) for Countries of the Near East Region, 1979; Hansell, Frankie; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 13 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Damascus, Syria; November 6th to 9th, 1979
- Integration of Women in Rural Development: Review and Analysis of FAO Policies, Programmes (1975-79) and Future Programme Trends (1980-85) for Countries of the Latin American Region, 1979; Carloni, Alice; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 13 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Caracas, Venezuela; November 12th to 16th, 1979
- Profile of Women in Agriculture and Rural Development in Rwanda, 1979-06; Home Economics and Social Programmes Services; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 29 pp (Box 1)
- Selected Bibliography of Literature on Appropriate Technology and Women, 1978-04; Lissner, Lauren; Home Economics and Social Programmes Services; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 27 pp (Box 1)
- Women in Development - Latin America: An Annotated Bibliography, 1978-04; Kharas, Purveen; Home Economics and Social Programmes Services; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 6 pp (Box 1)
- Women in Development - Africa: An Annotated Bibliography, 1978-04; Kharas, Purveen; Home Economics and Social Programmes Services; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 13 pp (Box 1)
- Profile of Women in Rural Development - Nepal, 1978-03; Kharas, Purveen; Home Economics and Social Programmes Services; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 22 pp (Box 1)
- Profile of Women in Rural Development - Sri Lanka, 1977-03; Kharas, Purveen; Home Economics and Social Programmes Services; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 35 pp (Box 1)
- Women in Development: A Selected Annotated Bibliography, 1978-04; Kharas, Purveen; Home Economics and Social Programmes Services; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 86 pp (Box 1)
- Review of Conditions Affecting the Integration of Rural Women in Development in Ten Countries of FAO's Asia and the Far East and Near East Regions, 1977; Hansell, Frankie; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 36 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Rome, Italy; September 19th to 23rd, 1977
- Introducing Population Concepts in Rural Women's Programmes, 1981; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 49 pp (Box 1)
- Country Statements, Summary Reports and Recommendations on Food Crops Utilization, 1985; Consultation on Home Economics and Agricultural Research; International Institute of Tropical Agriculture and the Home Economics Association of Africa; 101 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Ibadan, Nigeria; April 10th to 13th, 1985
- A Shift in the Wind: Women Ending Hunger, Undated; The Hunger Project; 12 pp (Box 1)
  No. 21
- Training for Agriculture and Rural Development, 1977; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 122 pp (Box 1)
  No. 7
- New Skills for Rural Women: Report of a Training Program for Twelve Malian Community Development Workers, 1977; Caughman, Susan L.; Service Quaker; American Friends Service Committee; 21 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Banjul, the Ghambia; June 7th to 15th, 1977
- Market Women in West Africa: Report of the Seminar on the Role of Women in Marketing Local Farm and Marine Produce, 1977; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 28 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Accra, Ghana; December 12th to 16th, 1977
- Reciprocal Relationships between Management of Family Resources and Economic and Social Factors Affecting Them, 1972; Presvelou, Clio; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 47 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Helsinki, Finland; July 17th to 21st, 1972
- Expert Consultation on "Mobilization of Agricultural and Educational Institutions to Accelerate Rural Women's Participation in Development", 1981; Jiménez, Mónica; Aylwin, Nidia; Gissi, Jorge; Jiménez, Marcela; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 61 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Tegucigalpa, Honduras; May 4th to 9th, 1981
- Importance, Development and Current Status of Consumer Movement in Europe and Elsewhere, 1969; Steenberg, Elisa; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 25 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Rome, Italy; September 22nd to 27th, 1969
- Institutions or Schools Specializing in Training in Home Economics, 1969; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 5 pp (Box 1)
- Assessment of Current Consumer Education Activities in Home Economics Programmes in Denmark, 1969; Madsen, Hanne Søndergaard; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 4 pp (Box 1)
- Information on Some Aspects of Family and Home Economics Research in Europe (Addendum to the Report), 1974; Home Economics and Social Programmes Services; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 8 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Athens, Greece; October 23rd to 30th, 1974; three copies
- Reasons for the Development of Agricultural Areas in Greece and the Contribution of the Extension Service in this Process, 1974; Taslikis, Ath.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 15 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Rome, Italy; October 23rd to 30th, 1974
- Motivation - Its Importance in the Process of Change and Implications for Advisory Work, 1974; Hruschka, Erna; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 25 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Athens, Greece; October 23rd to 30th, 1974
- The Participation of Women in Agricultural Organizations in Europe, 1980; Meynell, P. J.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 42 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Innsbruck, Austria; September 8th to 12th, 1980
- Estudio de Factibilidad Sobre la Necesidad de Formar Personal Tecnico para Programas de Desarrollo Familiar Rural en Mexico, 1980-04; Martinez, Edith; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 227 pp (Box 1)
- Women's Groups in Kenya: A Grass Roots Strategy for Rural Development, 1977-11; Pala, Achola O.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 20 pp (Box 1)
- Evolution of the Muslim Family in the Arab East, 1978; Prothro, Edwin T.; Diab, Lutfy N.; United Nations Economic and Social Council; 45 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Amman, Jordan; November 18th to 30th, 1978
- Notes on the Role of Rural Pakistani Women in Farming in the Northwest Frontier Province, 1977; Ashraf, Malik; 4 pp (Box 1)
- Various Perspectives on Using Women's Organizations in Development Programming, Undated; Hoskins, Marilyn W.; Office of Women in Development, United States Agency for International Development; 48 pp (Box 1)
- Report on FAO ad hoc Consultation on Programme Development in Home Economics in Africa, 1969; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 26 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Accra, Ghana; October 22nd to November 2nd, 1968
- Beliefs and Practices Related to Health, Nutrition and Child Rearing in Two Communities of Oman, 1973; UNICEF; Gulf Area Office; 91 pp (Box 1)
  Part IV: Marriage and Family in Mizwa and Sohar
- The Tribune: A Women and Development Quarterly, 1986; International Women's Tribune Centre, Inc.; 60 pp (Box 1)
  Newsletter 33/34, 4th QTR 1985 / 1st QTR 1986
- Modernization and the Changing Life Chances of Women in Low-Income Rural Families, 1979; Alcántara, Cynthia Hewitt de; United Nations Economic and Social Council; 59 pp (Box 1)
- Food Aid and the Role of Women in Development, 1976; World Food Programme; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 46 pp (Box 1)
- Human Nutrition in Tropical Africa: A Textbook for Health Workers with Special Reference to Community Health Problems in East Africa, 1965; Latham, Michael; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 278 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Sierra Leone: Planning of Home Economics Programmes for Rural and National Development, 1972; Janelid, Ingrid; Inter-Agency Committee on Home Economics; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 71 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the South Pacific Commission: Home Economics in the Community, 1963-1969, 1970; Eden, Elizabeth; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 73 pp (Box 1)
- Report to the Government of Somalia: Development of a National Programme of Home Economics, 1970; Almira, L. L.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 34 pp (Box 1)
- Report of the FAO/ECA/SIDA Seminar on Home Economics Development Planning for English-Speaking Countries in Africa, 1972; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 64 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia; March 6th to 24th, 1972
- Report of the Planning for Better Family Living Staff Orientation Training Session, 1971; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 64 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Rome, Italy; July 22nd to 31st, 1971
- Report on the FAO/UNDP Asia and the Far East Seminar on Strengthening Family Life, 1971; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 209 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Los Baños, the Philippines; April 28th to May 7th, 1971
- Communication Workshop for Rural Field Workers, Kenya, 1972; The Government of Kenya; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 115 pp (Box 1)
  Meeting: Nairobi; September 18th to 30th, 1972
- Informe at Gobierno de Colombia: La Facultad de Economia del Hogar de la Universidad de Caldas, 1968; Moore, Marian E.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 14 pp (Box 1)
- Message from the Village, 1978; Huston, Perdita; 160 pp (Box 2)
  Gift of Ludmilla Marin-Jenkins
- Teaching Better Nutrition: A Study of Approaches and Techniques, 1950-11; Ritchie, Jean A. S.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 155 pp (Box 2)
- Food and Nutrition Education in the Primary School: A Guide for its Introduction, 1971; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 111 pp (Box 2)
- Learning Better Nutrition: A Second Study of Approaches and Techniques, 1967; Ritchie, Jean A. S.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 276 pp (Box 2)
- International Women's Decade: A Balance Sheet, 1984-12-15; Mair, Lucille Mathurin; Centre for Women's Development Studies, New Delhi; 36 pp (Box 2)
- The Role of African Women in Rural Development: Research Priorities, 1974-06; Pala, Achola O.; Institute for Development Studies, University of Nairobi; 31 pp (Box 2)
- Sewing for Children: Practical Working Patterns, 1970; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 19 pp (Box 2)
  Includes sewing pattern and rubber sheet.
- Equipment Related to the Domestic Functions of Food Preparation, Handling and Storage, 1974; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 110 pp (Box 2)
- Rural Home Techniques: Food Preservation (Series 1), 1977; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 84 pp (Box 2)
- Taller de Capacitacion Sobre "Evaluacion de Proycetos de Generacion de Ingresos Para Mujeres Campesinas", 1988; Oficina Regional de FAO Para America Latina y El Caribe; 50 pp (Box 2)
- Report to the Government of Tanzania: The Home Economics Training Centre, Buchare, Musoma, Tanzania, 1971; Ritchie, Jean A. S.; Van der Meer, Janny; Reyes, Aurea C.; Lofgren, Ulla; Gip, Marta; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 66 pp (Box 2)
- Report on the FAO/SIDA Workshop for Intermediate-Level Instructors in Home Economics and Family-Oriented Programmes in East and Southern Africa, 1974; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 78 pp (Box 2)
  Meeting: Njoro, Kenya; May 1st to 14th, 1974
- Home Economics in the Context of Economic and Social Development, 1969; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 55 pp (Box 2)
- Report of a Seminar to Evaluate the Programme of the Home Economics Training Centre, Buhare, Musoma, Tanzania, 1971; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 61 pp (Box 2)
  Meeting: Buhare, Musoma, Tanzania; November 30th to December 7th, 1970
- Report to the Government of Tanzania: Teaching of Rural Home Ecnomics at Buhare Home Economics Training Centre, Musoma, 1972; Van der Meer, Janny; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 14 pp (Box 2)
- Report to the Government of Tanzania: Teaching of Textiles and Clothing/Arts and Handicrafts at Buhare Home Economics Training Centre, Musoma, 1972; Reyes, Aurea C.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 13 pp (Box 2)
- Report on the Expert Consultation on the Development of a Cooperative "Planning for Better Family Living" (PFBL) Programme, 1973; International Federation of Home Economics; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 139 pp (Box 2)
  Meeting: Saint-Germain-en-Laye, France; April 9th to 14th, 1973
- Report of the Fourth Session of the Working Party on Home Economics for Europe, 1975; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 28 pp (Box 2)
- Report on the FAO/UNFPA Seminar on Population Problems as Related to Food and Rural Development in the Near East, 1973; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 40 pp (Box 2)
  Meeting: Cairo, Egypt; December 11th to 20th, 1972
- The Changing Role of European Agriculture, 1972-06; Barberis, Corrado; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 52 pp (Box 2)